<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<message>Review by <writer>Brendan Caldwell</writer> <title>Former Features Editor</title>
Published on <entires date='2018-01-24'>Jan. 24, 2018</entires>
<comments num='83'>83 comments</comments>
<p num='1'><tag>Follow Subnautica</tag> <!-- this was a follower tag on the site I got this passage/review from -->
The best <type>survival games</type> are about conquering fear. Last year, when I first splashed about in <game>Subnautica’s</game> alien <body water='type'>ocean</body>, I was wary of leaving the shallow <location>reef</location> in which you first crash land. I eyed the hazy green water of the nearby <location>kelp forests</location> with fear, knowing it was full of <creature sea='1'>Stalkers</creature>, an aggressive <animal>fish</animal> whose body is mostly one long croc-like jaw. Today, I swim among these beasts, collecting <item>vines</item> and <item>seed pods</item> as they impotently pursue me through the weeds. I’ve become a proficient scavenger, making the journey from trouserless idiot to <movie><actor>Tom Hanks</actor> in Castaway’s</movie> third act. But even now there are places I do not like to go.</p>

<p num='2'>For those yet to dip their toes, <game>Subnautica’s</game> <type>survival</type> is familiar. You’ve got a food and <liquid>water</liquid> meter (although these can be turned off in an <gm>easier mode</gm> <!-- when i say gm her it means GameMode for any gamers that understand this -->), an oxygen meter and a health bar. The environment and your <spawn>lifepod</spawn> contains everything you’ll need to stay alive. If you do croak it from drowning or from becoming fish fodder, you'll respawn back in your <spawn>lifepod</spawn> having lost some of your items (although it's somewhat random and inconsistent in this punishment). There’s also a <item>radio</item> in your pod which, once repaired, will get the game’s plot rolling.</p>

<p num='3'>It’s a light story that encircles everything you do, like a friendly <animal>dolphin</animal> reminding you to check out this part of the sea, or dive down to that <location site='broken'>crash site</location>. It doesn’t interfere with your daily fishing, instead giving you a focus, some extra motivation to stay alive on this vast blue expanse.</p></message>